## CLOUD SOLUTION ARCHITECT

Professional Summary

Infrastructure lead with 7 years' experience with various cloud product (majorly in Openstack) by supporting in both IT and Telco cloud. Experienced with integrating Openstack with multiple hypervisor by using third party tool in self-paced enterprise hybrid cloud platform.

## Skills

- Technical Analysis
- Customer proposals
- Cloud services
- Scripting skills
- Interpersonal Communication Project Management
- Storage virtualization
- Extensive knowledge of Linux software
- Linux and Unix specialist
- Knowledge with RedHat
- Teamwork
- Excellent work ethic

## Work History

Cloud Solution Architect 01/2020 to Current Rockwell Automation, Inc. â€" York, PA

- Openstack & Cloud administrator with over 6+ years of experience in Openstack, cloud computing, Virtualization, IAAS support & management.
- Experience in preparing Low level design & High level design for Teleco Openstack based cloud for major telecom clients like Tmobile, Freedom mobile, AT&T, bell mobility, Comcast, Telus, Vodofone india, Bharti India and few government projects.
- Experienced in deploying large cloud environment with more than 150 compute nodes in each cloud.
- Experience in managing multiple private clouds for enterprises on Bare metal, Virtual Machines and Containers to address different project needs.
- Experience in Openstack components Neutron, Nova, Cinder, Horizon, Ceilometer, Heat, Glance and Swift.
- Experience in deploying Cloud both automatically using Fuel (Mirantis) and manual deployment (Redhat)
- Experience in verifying Openstack environment in Docker Containers for Sanity tests before upgrading production environment.
- Experienced with managing Kubernetes cluster with more than 150 worker nodes (Large environment for development project)
- Experience in DevOps process using Jenkins, Ansible for On Demand Openstack deployment.
- Experience in creating/managing multiple tenants in a cloud,
- Creating quotas, triggering alarms when certain thresholds are reached, creating network and creating/customizing heat templates.
- Expertise in troubleshooting Openstack issues from fault detection, fault isolation and resolving many key issues.
- Experienced in supporting large scale multi-tenant infrastructure level services.
- Experience in supporting private cloud environments housing multiple tenants in multiple networks.
- Automating deployment and other validation tasks through developing scripts.
- Knowledge in python and OOPs concepts.
- Doing scale-in & scale out the Openstack environment based on customer requirements.
- Experience installing, configuring and managing Linux based systems and applications via automation and configuration management tools such as ansible.
- Excellent interpersonal skills, effective troubleshooting, and customer handling skills.
- EMC: Configuration of storage servers and creating LUNs, storage pool, storage groups & network initiators.
- Understanding and preparing the manifest files such as YAML and JSON for cloud & VNF/VMs deployment.
- Having experience with Continuous deployment and continuous integration (CI/CD) using GIT, GITHUB, docker hub, & Jenkins
- Creating the solution document for the new cloud deployment by having network connectivity layout, storage configuration details & cloud rack server details.
- Knowledge and working experience in Kubernetes and Docker environment.
- Having knowledge in VNF, SDN, MANO, VNFO, VNFM, VNFD.
- Deployment and troubleshooting of VMs in the Openstack & VMware environment.
- Digging from network level in Openstack OVS & neutron agent, VXLAN & VLAN, Linux bridges.

# Openstack Cloud Solution Engineer 05/2018 to 01/2020

Global Data Consultants â€" York, PA

- Automation Writing ansible playbooks to create application deployment stack, writing bash script for automation to manage the complete cloud orchestration.
- Docker container orchestration Specifically creating docker file to launch container-based application and working with docker.
- Python automation: (1) Developed python module which will pull complete ILO information, like CPU, memory, nic, storage and health summary and status. Also, it will do some major task related to POWER, SNMP, ONE TIME boot etc. (it will be more useful while doing CBIS deployment with huge number of blades. (also using HP providing ILO module on my script to get more throughput)) (2) Automated CBAM deployment by doing one touch installation possible.
- Performance tuning Computes â€" specialist in OVS, SRIOV, DPDK, NUMA and CPU Spinning hands-on.
- CBIS, CBAM and CBND: All three products were deployed / integrated successfully on Indian teleco customer environment multiple
- Cloud deployment I will deploying Openstack private cloud by Undercloud then Overcloud (TripleO Openstack architecture) and followed by post installation activity.

- Service level HA Services are configured with pacemaker cluster, I will be managing pacemaker cluster as well. (having hands on pacemaker resource handling)
- CEPH Storage I will be deploying & managing CEPH storage cluster, creating storage pool, manage OSD & DATA, recovering PG etc.
- Undercloud Operation I will do deploying Scale OUT / Scale IN, Controller replacement, CEPH and PCS software management. Kolla Ansible: having hands-on kola ansible deployment on lab environment.
- Overcloud Operation Project, user, Quota, flavor, image, Volume, Network creation using it launching VM / VNF, writing ansible
  creation to create application stack, migrating the VM from one compute to another either online / Offline migrations. Converting volume to
  image / vise Vera etc.

### UNIX Administrator 09/2014 to 04/2018

IBM India Pvt Ltd, Michelin Tire Corporation â€" City, STATE

- The project deals with 500 UNIX Servers supporting to the Michelin Tire corporation which is a product manufacture sector primarily located in North America within the agreed SLA's.
- Main aim is to provide support and involve Change Management, Process Management and Incident Management and Release Management to the Production and Non-Prod Servers which are in use also include RFS.
- Roles and Responsibilities on IBM:.
- Working with the high severity Incidents and changes ranging from Sev1 to Sev4.
- Patching of servers as per the scheduled scan from the repo server which involves raising changes before the Implementation.
- Day-to-Day Activity involves working on Incidents, Changes, Request, and other activities like Filesystem related issues, Availability Alerts, NTP and network related issues.
- Raising case with Vendors for hardware part replacement and hardware related issues, such as Array controller battery, Fault hard drive, faulty memory, faulty cache replacements.
- Analyzing Linux Server alerts and Troubleshooting its issue.
- Managing LVM on servers, Creating/Altering/Extending filesystems.
- Attending bridge call hosted by Incident Managements for critical issues.
- Configuring and upgrading the vmware tools on virtual servers.
- Attending meetings like Check point, Change Advisory Board (CAB), Top 5 Critical servers for each day.
- Working with Tivoli End Point Manager for Monitoring and Tivoli Scheduler for data backup using Tape drive & Tape Library.
- Working on OS upgrades, Hosts rebuild Linux and Decommissioning hosts.
- Working with ITS support team for any part replacement at hardware level.
- Working with RFS activity involving new servers build as per business requirement.
- Working with BAU activity involving day to day activity such as Incidents, Service request, and Changes.
- Identify incident and problem root causes and document resolutions in designated knowledge web link.
- Working with different vendors for any hardware issue and with REDHAT for any clarification at OS level.
- Attending Bridge Call, on call, CAB meet, hosted by Problem & Change Managements for critical issues.
- Managing Security Compliance and install latest patches as per APAR/CIRAT Management.

## Hardware Experience

- Strong knowledge on Server platforms: Hp Enclosure setup, HP Virtual Connect Manager, HP Onboard Administrator, Dell PowerEdge servers, HP Rack servers Gen9 and Gen10 models.
- Strong knowledge on Airframe Open rack, Airframe Rack Mounted and Airframe bybrid models
- Understanding and having work experience in L2/L3 switches and connectivity's.
- Understanding the BIOS, switch level configurations.
- Upgrading the firmware, BIOS, system ROM versions.
- Creating the architectural diagram for the new cloud network connectivity.
- Preparing and instructing the hardware team to do the cabling as per the prepared solution.
- Experienced in storage server EMC VNX 5400 model â€" Deployment and configuration. Basic understanding about CISCO and HP switches.

# Certifications

- Completed RH280 Red Hat Certified specialist in openshift Administration Exam by Redhat., in Aug 2019
- Completed RH210 Red Hat Certified Openstack (Cloud) Administrator Exam by Redhat., in May 2018
- Completed EX407 Red Hat Certified Specialist in Ansible Automation. Exam in Dec 2017
- Completed EX300 Red Hat Certified Engineer Exam by Redhat., in Jun 2016
- Completed EX300 Red Hat Certified System Administrator Exam by Redhat., in Jun 2016
- Completed RH442 Red Hat Enterprise System Monitoring and Performance Tuning Training by Redhat., in Jun 2015
- Completed RH436 Red Hat Enterprise Storage Management Training by Redhat., in Aug 2015

# Accomplishments

# ACHIEVEMENT.

- Received "Best planning and implementation for datacentre infrastructure†award from the customer "Bharti India" (2018)
- Appreciation certificate from Michelin CIO for outstanding dedication and commitment towards client success.

- Appreciation certificate from France delivery head IBM for successful completion of ONC center migration project 2017 and commitment towards client success.
- Received applause award two times for implementation. (2016)
- Outstanding performer award (2015)

#### Education

Bachelor of Computer Science And Engineering: Computer Engineering 2014 B.Tech [ Pondicherry University ] - City High School Degree: Computer Science 03/2010 Nivedha Matric Hsc School - City SSLC 03/2008 Nivedha Matric Hsc School - City